（ヤサコ）
人は死んだらどうなるのか
その心がどこに行くのか―
What happens to people when they die?
Where do their souls go?
本当のことは誰も知りません
Nobody knows the truth.
苦しい[くるしい]:painful|needy|forced (smile, joke)||
（少女）苦しい… 苦しいの…
I'm in pain... so much pain...
（ハラケン）誰？
Who are you?
Save me...
助ける[たすける]:to save|to help|to aid|
（少女）助けて… 誰か助けて…
Someone, save me...
（ハラケン）どこ？
Where are you?
助ける[たすける]:to save|to help|to aid|
（少女）出られない 助けて…
I can't get out...
Help me!
助ける[たすける]:to save|to help|to aid|, あげる:to raise/to elevate|to do up (one's hair)
助けてあげる！　どこにいるの？
I'll help you!
Where are you?
助ける[たすける]:to save|to help|to aid|
（少女）助けて…
Save me.
同じ[おなじ, おんなじ]:same/identical|(usu. part of a 'nara' conditional) anyway, 夢[ゆめ]:dream
ハァ… また同じ夢だ
The same dream again...
いける:to arrange (flowers)/to plant|living, いける:to be good (at)/to go well|to look (taste, etc.) good, 病院[びょういん]:hospital
いけない
今日は病院に行く日だった
That's not good.
I have to go to the hospital today.
The Last Summer Vacation
（フミエ）ヤサコ！
Yasako!
泳ぐ[およぐ]:to swim
どうしたの？　泳がないの？
What's wrong?
Aren't you swimming?
No.
元気[げんき]:lively/full of spirit|healthy
今日は元気ないのね
You don't feel good today, do you?
うっ… 何すんのよ！
What the hell?!
おらっ！
Take this!
一体[いったい]:...the heck (e.g. "what the heck?")|one object|one form||, 気[き]:spirit|nature|motivation||, 気[げ]:seeming/giving the appearance of/giving one the feeling of
（ヤサコ）天沢(あまさわ)さん
一体 何をする気なんだろう？
Amasawa...
What are you planning to do?
兄[あに]:elder brother/older brother, 兄[けい]:elder brother|pronoun or suffix used in reference to an older brother figure/Mister, 戻る[もどる]:to turn back (e.g. half-way)|to return|to recover (e.g. something lost)|, 戻る[もとる]:to go against/to act contrary to/to deviate from
（イサコ）
私の兄は戻れなくなったんだ
My brother...
couldn't come back here anymore.
魂[たましい, だましい]:soul/spirit, 魂[こん]:Yang energy/spirit, 電脳[でんのう]:computer|cyberbrain/digital brain, 体[からだ]:body|torso|build||, 体[たい]:body|shape|substance||, あっち:that way (direction distant from both speaker and listener)/over there|that one (something physically distant from both speaker and listener, or something not visible but known by both speaker and listener)
魂は電脳の体とともに
あっちに行ったままだ
His soul, just like his cyberbody,
ended up on "the other side."
今も
Even now.
あっち:that way (direction distant from both speaker and listener)/over there|that one (something physically distant from both speaker and listener, or something not visible but known by both speaker and listener)
あっち？
The other side...
子供[こども]:child/children
（解説者）子供のウワサでは―
Among kids, apparently there's a spell called "encode" that's pretty popular.
暗号[あんごう]:code/password/cipher, まじない:charm/incantation/spell, はやる:to be popular/to come into fashion|to be prevalent, はやる:to be in high spirits/to be impatient/to be hotblooded
暗号という おまじないが
はやってるそうですよ
暗号[あんごう]:code/password/cipher
（司会者）ほう 暗号ですか
Oh, encode?
アイテム:item, 集める[あつめる]:to collect/to assemble/to gather
（解説者）
それでキラバグという
アイテムを集めると
And then, the story goes that if you collect items called "kirabugs,"
願い事[ねがいごと]:wish/dream/prayer, かなう:to come true (wish)|to be suited, 話[はなし]:talk/speech|discussions, 話[わ]:counter for stories, episodes of TV series, etc.
なんでも願い事が
かなうとかいう話で
any wish you have can come true.
Kirabugs...
キラバグ
（看護師）原川(はらかわ)さん
Harakawa!
メガネ:spectacles/glasses
あっ メガネは？
And the glasses?
外す[はずす]:to unfasten|to remove|to leave|, 待合室[まちあいしつ]:waiting room
（看護師）中では外してね
待合室なら使っていいけど
Take them off there.
You can leave them in the waiting room as well.
（医者）君のおばさんから―
Your aunt told me, "Check him thoroughly."
徹底的[てっていてき]:thorough/complete, 調べる[しらべる]:to examine/to investigate/to check up
徹底的に調べてくれって
言われててね
今日は１人で来たの？
Did you come alone today?
はい
Yes.
先日[せんじつ]:the other day/a few days ago, 大学病院[だいがくびょういん]:university hospital/teaching hospital, 結果[けっか]:result/consequence|coming to fruition, かぎり:limit/limits|degree
先日の大学病院の結果を
見るかぎりでは―
When we examined him the other day at University Hospital,
全く[まったく]:really|indeed|good grief (expression of exasperation), 異常[いじょう]:strangeness/abnormality/disorder
全く異常がなかったよ
we didn't find anything wrong.
叔母[おば, はくぼ]:aunt, メガネ:spectacles/glasses, 関連性[かんれんせい]:relatedness/associativity/relation
君の叔母さんは
メガネとの関連性を―
Your aunt obstinately insists that this is related to the glasses, you know.
しつこい:insistent/obstinate|too rich (taste, etc.), 主張[しゅちょう]:claim/insistence/assertion
しつこく主張してるんだけど
医学[いがく]:medical science/medicine
今の医学では―
But present-day medicine
メガネ:spectacles/glasses, 頭痛[ずつう]:headache, 不整脈[ふせいみゃく]:irregular pulse/arrhythmia, 関係[かんけい]:relation|participation|influence||, 証明[しょうめい]:proof/verification/certification
メガネと頭痛や不整脈の関係は
証明されてないんだ
has not shown any relationship between headaches or uneven heartbeat and the glasses.
ああ もういいよ
It's okay, now.
他[ほか]:other (place, thing, person)|outside|nothing except|, 他[た]:other (esp. people and abstract matters)
あの… オバちゃん
他に何か言ってましたか？
Err...
Did my aunt say something else?
メガネ:spectacles/glasses, 取り上げる[とりあげる]:to pick up|to adopt|to take away|
（医者）
“メガネを取り上げたほうが
いいでしょうか？”って言ってたな
She asked if she should confiscate your glasses.
きっと:surely/undoubtedly|sternly, 本気[ほんき]:seriousness/earnestness/truth
ハハハハッ
きっと本気じゃないさ
She can't be serious.
So, no pain in your head or heart, right?
頭痛[ずつう]:headache, 心臓[しんぞう]:heart|guts|central part
で 頭痛と心臓は
なんともないんだね？
全然[ぜんぜん]:not at all (with neg. verb)|wholly/entirely
いえ もう全然…
No, not anymore...
検査[けんさ]:inspection (e.g. customs, factory)/examination/scan (e.g. MRI, PET, etc.), 結果[けっか]:result/consequence|coming to fruition, 一致[いっち]:coincidence|conformity|cooperation
（医者）そうか
じゃあ 検査結果と一致するな
I see.
So it's exactly like the test results said.
メガネ:spectacles/glasses, 疲れる[つかれる]:to get tired|to be worn out (e.g. of well used objects)|to starve, 医者[いしゃ]:(medical) doctor/physician
まあ メガネは目が疲れるし
医者としても―
Well, the glasses do strain your eyes,
and as a doctor, I can only urge you to reduce their use, but...
ほどほど:moderate
ほどほどにしとけと
言うべきところなんだけど
一[いち]:one|best|first||, 一[ひとつ]:one|for one thing|only||, 手放す[てばなす]:to let go of|to part with (e.g. a possession)|to send away (e.g. one's child)|, 偉い[えらい]:great/excellent|awful, 言える[いえる]:to be possible to say/to be able to say
僕らも 一日中 手放せないし
そう偉いことは言えないね
You see, even we can't do without them during the day,
so I can't really preach to you.
子供[こども]:child/children, もっと:(some) more/even more/longer
でもね 子供は もっと―
But you know,
I think kids would be better off playing with something more real.
本物[ほんもの]:genuine article/real thing/real deal, 遊ぶ[あそぶ, あすぶ]:to play|to mess about (with alcohol, gambling, philandery, etc.)|to be idle||, 遊ぶ[すさぶ]:to grow wild/to rage|to do something one enjoys, しれる:to become known/to come to light|to be known
本物の何かで遊んだほうが
いいかもしれないね
ちゃんと:diligently/seriously|perfectly, 触れる[ふれる]:to touch|to experience|to touch on a subject||
ちゃんと手で触れる何かで
With something you can touch with your hands, perhaps.
放射線科[ほうしゃせんか]:radiology department, 順番[じゅんばん]:turn (in line)/order of things/sequential order
（看護師）さあ あとは
放射線科の順番を待ってね
Fine. Now go wait for the X-ray test.
I can't go to the library.
図書館[としょかん, ずしょかん]:library, 行[ぎょう]:line (i.e. of text)|carya (austerities)|samskara (formations)|, 行[こう]:going|type of classical Chinese verse (usu. an epic)|district (of similar merchants)|
図書館 行けなくってごめんね
Sorry!
Yesterday's part is in the shared folder, so...
昨日[きのう, さくじつ]:yesterday, 共有[きょうゆう]:joint ownership/co-ownership/sharing, フォルダ:folder
昨日の分は
共有フォルダに入ってるから
（フミエ）じゃあ
（ヤサコ）うん
Bye!
あら？
Oh?
Hurry!
急ぐ[いそぐ]:to hurry/to rush/to hasten
（ガチャギリ）急げ！
古い[ふるい]:old (not person)/aged/ancient, 空間[くうかん]:space/room/airspace, 空間[あきま]:vacancy/room for rent or lease, なんて:how ..!/what ..!|what (questioning), なんて:such as/(things) like|exclamation, 広い[ひろい]:spacious/vast/wide
まだ古い空間があったなんて…
それも こんなに広い
I'd never have guessed there was obsolete Space here.
And this big!
見える[みえる]:to be seen|to look|to come, 見える[まみえる]:to have an audience|to face (an enemy)|to serve (esp. as one's wife)
（ガチャギリ）本当に
サッチーには見えてないんだな？
So, Satchii can't really spot us.
Yeah, if you don't make a mistake.
（イサコ）ああ
お前たちがヘマさえしなければな
I'm sure there are kirabugs around here.
必ず[かならず]:always/without exception/necessarily, 近く[ちかく]:near|nearly (e.g. "it took nearly one year")|shortly
キラバグは 必ずこの近くにある
Don't let your guard down.
気を抜く[きをぬく]:to lose focus/to let one's mind wander/to relax one's attention
気を抜くな
天沢さん キラバグで何を？
What does Amasawa plan to do with the kirabugs?
今朝[けさ, こんちょう]:this morning, 顔色[かおいろ, がんしょく]:complexion/one's colour|countenance, 悪い[わるい]:bad|evil|unprofitable||, 悪い[にくい]:hateful/abominable|amazing, みたい:-like/sort of/similar to
（オバちゃん）今朝
ちょっと顔色が悪かったみたいね
So, this morning you were quite pale.
姉さん[ねえさん, あねさん]:elder sister|(vocative) young lady|miss (referring to a waitress, etc.)|
姉さんから聞いたわ
I heard it from Sis.
I just had a dream.
夢を見る[ゆめをみる]:to dream/to have a dream, 夢[ゆめ]:dream
（ハラケン）
夢を見ただけだよ カンナの夢
A dream about Kanna.
Kanna was still stuck somewhere, suffering...
留まる[とまる]:to stop (moving)|to stop (doing, working, being supplied)|to alight, 留まる[とどまる]:to remain/to abide|to be limited to, 苦しむ[くるしむ]:to suffer/to groan/to be worried
（ハラケン）カンナは まだ
どこかに留(とど)まっていて苦しんでる
At some point we met, and she wanted to talk with me.
話す[はなす]:to talk|to tell|to speak (a language), たがる:wanting to .../eager to .../curious to ...
僕に会って話したがってる
忘れる[わすれる]:to forget/to leave carelessly/to be forgetful of, なさる:to do
（オバちゃん）
もうカンナのことは忘れなさい
Now forget about Kanna already.
こないだ:the other day/lately/recently, みたい:-like/sort of/similar to, 起こる[おこる]:to occur/to happen
もし また
こないだみたいなことが起こったら
If something like last time happens again...
今度[こんど]:this time|next time|recently, メガネ:spectacles/glasses, 取り上げる[とりあげる]:to pick up|to adopt|to take away|
今度こそ メガネを取り上げるわ
I'll confiscate your glasses.
関係[かんけい]:relation|participation|influence||, 自由[じゆう]:freedom/liberty/as it pleases you, 研究[けんきゅう]:study/research/investigation
（ハラケン）
関係ない 自由研究なんだ
That's not related.
It's for my independent research.
ウソつき:liar (sometimes said with not much seriousness)/fibber
ウソつき
Liar.
"Independent research" is just a pretext, isn't it?
自由[じゆう]:freedom/liberty/as it pleases you, 研究[けんきゅう]:study/research/investigation, なんて:how ..!/what ..!|what (questioning), なんて:such as/(things) like|exclamation, 口実[こうじつ]:excuse/pretext
自由研究なんて口実なんでしょ？
Ken, Kanna is dead.
ケンちゃん カンナは死んだのよ
Bye. I have some more examinations.
検査[けんさ]:inspection (e.g. customs, factory)/examination/scan (e.g. MRI, PET, etc.)
（ハラケン）
じゃあ 僕 まだ検査があるから
都市[とし]:town/city/municipal, 伝説[でんせつ]:tradition/legend/folklore, いろいろ:various|various colors (colours)
（解説者）都市伝説にも
いろいろあって
There are many urban legends,
and among them, one says that kirabugs are a passage to another world.
異界[いかい]:spirit world/underworld/the next world, 扉[とびら]:door/gate|title page, 開く[ひらく]:to open|to bloom|to open (for business, e.g. in the morning)||, 開く[あく]:to open (e.g. doors)|to open (e.g. business, etc.)|to be empty||
中にはキラバグは
異界への扉を開く―
通路[つうろ]:passage/pathway/roadway
通路だというのも
あるそうです
Kirabugs?
キラバグ
Isako!
ひょっと:possibly/perhaps|unintentionally
イサコ ひょっとして…
Could it be that...
Urban legends...
都市[とし]:town/city/municipal, 伝説[でんせつ]:tradition/legend/folklore
都市伝説 キラバグ…
Kirabugs...
質問[しつもん]:question/inquiry/enquiry
あっ 質問してる人がいる
There's a question from someone.
"What are kirabugs?"
バグる:to behave buggily (software)/to act up/to behave strangely
〝キラバグって
なんですか？ 〞
"The word kirabug apparently started to circulate after the metabugs."
言葉[ことば, けとば]:language|word|speech, 語る[かたる]:to talk about|to recite|to indicate, 始める[はじめる]:to start|to open (e.g. a store)|to start ...
“キラバグという言葉が
語られ始めたのは―”
"Metabugs are a mysterious cybersubstance often seen in Daikoku city,"
後[あと]:behind|after|after one's death||, 後[のち]:later|future|after one's death|
“メタバグより
後だと言われている”
大黒[だいこく]:god of wealth|monk's wife, 市[いち]:market/fair, 市[し]:city, 謎[なぞ]:riddle/puzzle|enigmatic, 電脳[でんのう]:computer|cyberbrain/digital brain, 物質[ぶっしつ]:material/substance|matter
“メタバグは大黒市(だいこくし)で
よく見られる謎の電脳物質で”
"but it is unknown where or how they are generated."
生み出す[うみだす]:to create|to invent|to give birth to
“どこから どのように
生み出されるのかは―”
全く[まったく]:really|indeed|good grief (expression of exasperation), 確認[かくにん]:confirmation/verification/validation
“全く確認されていない”
琥珀[こはく]:amber, 封ずる[ふうずる]:to seal (letter)|to prevent/to forbid, 封ずる[ほうずる]:to enfeoff, 昆虫[こんちゅう]:insect/bug, 化石[かせき]:fossil/petrifaction/fossilization
“メタバグには琥珀(こはく)に封じられた
昆虫化石のように”
"In metabugs, just like insect fossils sealed in amber,"
時折[ときおり, ときより]:sometimes, 音[おと, ね]:sound|note|fame|, 文章[ぶんしょう]:sentence/article|(writing) style, データ:data/datum, 含む[ふくむ, くくむ]:to contain|to hold in the mouth|to bear in mind|
“時折 音や文章といった
データが含まれている”
"data that we might call sounds or texts is sometimes found."
マニアック:maniac (as in rabid sport fan)/enthusiast, 価値[かち]:value/worth/merit, 生む[うむ]:to give birth/to bear (child)|to produce, 一時[ひととき, いっとき]:moment|former times|two-hour period, 一時[いちじ]:one o'clock|once|for a time|, 高値[たかね]:high price, 取り引き[とりひき]:transactions/dealings/business
“それがマニアックな価値を生み
一時は高値で取り引きされた”
"This gave rise to a collecting frenzy,"
"and, for a while, they traded at high prices."
さらに:furthermore/again/after all, 価値[かち]:value/worth/merit
“だが そのうち
さらに価値のあるメタバグがある”
"But later, rumors spread that there was an even more valuable kind of metabug."
広まる[ひろまる]:to spread/to be propagated
“…とのウワサが広まった”
“それがキラバグである”
"That was the kirabug."
オカルト:occult, 的[てき]:-like/typical, 的[まと]:mark/target, 存在[そんざい]:existence/being, でもある:to also be (formal, literary)/implies that as well as the earlier stated this is also the case|to be ... or something
“だが キラバグは
オカルト的な存在でもある”
"But kirabugs are also an occult concept."
電脳[でんのう]:computer|cyberbrain/digital brain, 空間[くうかん]:space/room/airspace, 空間[あきま]:vacancy/room for rent or lease, 奇妙[きみょう]:strange/queer/curious, 物質[ぶっしつ]:material/substance|matter
“この電脳空間にあってはならない
奇妙な物質だというのだ”
"They are said to be a sinister substance that should never occur in this Space."
伝説[でんせつ]:tradition/legend/folklore, 集める[あつめる]:to collect/to assemble/to gather, 現れる[あらわれる]:to appear/to come in sight|to be expressed (e.g. emotions)
“ある伝説は キラバグを集めると
ミチコさんが現れて―”
"According to some legends, if you collect a lot of kirabugs, Miss Michiko will appear,"
願い事[ねがいごと]:wish/dream/prayer, かなえる:to grant (request, wish)/to answer (prayer)|to fulfill (conditions)
“なんでも願い事を
かなえてくれるといい”
"and she will grant you any wish."
大人[おとな, だいにん]:adult, 大人[たいじん]:man of substance or virtue|giant|adult, 含める[ふくめる]:to include (in a group or scope)|to instruct|to include (a nuance)||, 目当て[めあて]:mark|purpose|sight (on a firearm), マニア:enthusiast
“大人も含め
キラバグ目当てのマニアが”
"The mania for collecting metabugs was a big craze in Daikoku City for a while, even among adults."
大黒[だいこく]:god of wealth|monk's wife, 市[いち]:market/fair, 市[し]:city, 殺到[さっとう]:rush/flood/deluge, 時期[じき]:time/season|soon
“大黒市に殺到した時期もあった”
結局[けっきょく]:after all|conclusion|ending of a game of Go, 作り話[つくりばなし]:fiction/made-up story/fable, 収束[しゅうそく]:conclusion|gathering and bundling|convergence|, やがて:before long/soon|almost, 忘れ去る[わすれさる]:to forget completely/to leave behind
“だが 結局 作り話として収束し
やがて忘れ去られていった”
"But in the end, people came to regard kirabugs as fiction,"
"and before long, they will be totally forgotten."
願い事[ねがいごと]:wish/dream/prayer
なんでも願い事を…
Any wish...
"What happens if you collect metabugs?"
集める[あつめる]:to collect/to assemble/to gather, どんな:what/what kind of|(with -temo, demo, etc.) any(body, thing, means, etc.), 起こる[おこる]:to occur/to happen
“キラバグを集めると
どんなことが起こるんですか？”
"Only once has a message been posted on a board about how to use kirabugs in a plausible way."
一度[いちど, ひとたび]:once|temporarily|one degree, 使い道[つかいみち]:purpose/utility|way to use something, ネット:network, 掲示板[けいじばん]:bulletin board/display board|electronic bulletin board
“一度だけキラバグの使い道が
ネットの掲示板で―”
まことしやか:plausible (e.g. of a rumour)/believable (e.g. of a story)/specious (e.g. of an argument), 語る[かたる]:to talk about|to recite|to indicate, ことがある:(something) has occurred/to have done (something)|(something) happens on occasions
“まことしやかに
語られたことがあった”
本来[ほんらい]:originally|essentially|proper
“キラバグは 本来―”
"Basically, kirabugs are a program that connects to a hidden Space, "
隔離[かくり]:isolation/segregation/separation, 空間[くうかん]:space/room/airspace, 空間[あきま]:vacancy/room for rent or lease, 接続[せつぞく]:connection|changing trains|conjunction, プログラム:program/programme
“ある隔離された空間に接続する
プログラムであり”
集める[あつめる]:to collect/to assemble/to gather, 起動[きどう]:startup/booting up/activation, ことにより:by (means of)/by doing/due to
“それを集めて
起動することにより―”
"and if you collect them and then start them up,"
あっち:that way (direction distant from both speaker and listener)/over there|that one (something physically distant from both speaker and listener, or something not visible but known by both speaker and listener), 通路[つうろ]:passage/pathway/roadway, 開く[ひらく]:to open|to bloom|to open (for business, e.g. in the morning)||, 開く[あく]:to open (e.g. doors)|to open (e.g. business, etc.)|to be empty||
“あっちとの通路を開くのだ”
"you can open a passage to 'the other side'."
（ハラケン）ヤサコ
（ヤサコ）ハッ！
Yasako!
（ヤサコ･ハラケン）
す… すみません
I-I'm sorry!
なさる:to do, 怖い[こわい]:scary/frightening|(I'm) afraid, ページ:page, 読む[よむ]:to read|to count|to guess
ごめんなさい
ちょっと怖いページを読んでたから
Sorry.
I was reading a really scary page.
怖い[こわい]:scary/frightening|(I'm) afraid, ページ:page
（ハラケン）怖いページ？
A scary page?
A page about kirabugs.
ページ:page
キラバグのページ
古い[ふるい]:old (not person)/aged/ancient, 空間[くうかん]:space/room/airspace, 空間[あきま]:vacancy/room for rent or lease, 見つける[みつける, みっける]:to discover|to locate|to be used to seeing
あっ そうだ
今日 古い空間 見つけたの
Oh, by the way!
I found an obsolete Space today.
ホント:truth/reality/actuality
ホントに？
Really?
It's north of here.
場所[ばしょ]:place|room|basho, 北[きた]:north|the North|North Korea|, 北[ペー]:north wind tile|winning hand with a pung (or kong) of north wind tiles
場所は ここより北のほう
でも どうやって？
But how...
偶然[ぐうぜん]:coincidence|by chance|contingency (philosophy), 見かける[みかける]:to (happen to) see/to notice/to catch sight of
偶然 天沢さんを見かけて…
I accidentally happened to meet Amasawa...
イサコを？
Isako?
（ヤサコ）そうだ
その天沢さんのことなんだけど…
Right, about Amasawa...
（ハラケン）イサコが？
Isako?
都市[とし]:town/city/municipal, 伝説[でんせつ]:tradition/legend/folklore, つなぎ合わせる[つなぎあわせる]:to connect/to join/to join or tie or knot together
（ヤサコ）うん… 都市伝説とか
そういうのをつなぎ合わせると
Those urban legends...
I've pieced it all together:
集める[あつめる]:to collect/to assemble/to gather
天沢さんが
キラバグを集めてるのは
The reason why Amasawa is collecting kirabugs
お兄さん[おにいさん]:older brother/elder brother|(vocative) young man, 意識[いしき]:consciousness|awareness|mano-vijnana (mental consciousness, cognizer of sensory information), 取り戻す[とりもどす]:to take back/to regain/to get back
お兄さんの意識を取り戻すために…
is to bring back her brother's consciousness.
みたい:-like/sort of/similar to
フフ… バカみたいね
That's silly!
そんなこと
本当にあるわけないよね
There's no way something like that could turn out to be true!
ことがある:(something) has occurred/to have done (something)|(something) happens on occasions
（ハラケン）でも もし本当に
そんなことがあるなら…
But...
If this did happen to be true...
意識[いしき]:consciousness|awareness|mano-vijnana (mental consciousness, cognizer of sensory information), 電脳[でんのう]:computer|cyberbrain/digital brain, 空間[くうかん]:space/room/airspace, 空間[あきま]:vacancy/room for rent or lease, しまう:to finish/to stop|to close (a business, etc.), 肉体[にくたい]:the body/the flesh, 切り離す[きりはなす]:to detach/to decapitate/to cut loose
意識だけ電脳空間に行ってしまって
肉体と切り離されてしまったら
If just your consciousness went into cyberspace,
and got separated from your physical body...
どんな:what/what kind of|(with -temo, demo, etc.) any(body, thing, means, etc.), 感じ[かんじ]:feeling/sense/impression
どんな感じなんだろう？
What would it feel like?
意識[いしき]:consciousness|awareness|mano-vijnana (mental consciousness, cognizer of sensory information), 残る[のこる]:to remain/to be left, 痛み[いたみ]:pain/ache|damage, 苦しみ[くるしみ]:pain/anguish/distress
意識は残ってるから
痛みとか苦しみとか
As your consciousness is still somewhere,
you might still continue to feel pain,
気持ち[きもち]:feeling|preparedness|thanks|, ずっと:continuously in some state (for a long time, distance)/throughout|much (better, etc.), 残る[のこる]:to remain/to be left, 続ける[つづける]:to continue/to keep up/to keep on, しれる:to become known/to come to light|to be known
気持ちは ずっと
残り続けてるのかもしれない
or sadness.
If feelings like pain,
苦しみ[くるしみ]:pain/anguish/distress, 悲しい[かなしい]:sad/sorrowful, 気持ち[きもち]:feeling|preparedness|thanks|
もし 苦しみとか
悲しい気持ちとか
or sadness...
そういうものが…
If these feelings...
原因[げんいん]:cause/origin/source, 作る[つくる]:to make|to prepare (food)|to raise||, 埋め合わせる[うめあわせる]:to make amends/to compensate for/to make up for, 癒やす[いやす]:to heal/to cure, あげる:to raise/to elevate|to do up (one's hair), かぎり:limit/limits|degree
その原因を作った人が埋め合わせて
癒やしてあげないかぎり―
If the person at the source of these feelings can't heal them...
永遠[えいえん]:eternity/perpetuity/immortality, 消える[きえる]:to go out/to vanish/to disappear
永遠に消えないとしたら…
And if they never went away...
隠す[かくす]:to hide/to conceal
ハラケン 何か隠してる？
Haraken, are you hiding something?
（ヤサコ）
もし何か 誰にも言わずに
If you are, say,
planning to do something dangerous,
危ない[あぶない]:dangerous|in danger|uncertain||
危ないこととか
しようとしてるんだとしたら…
that you can't tell anyone about...
（ハラケン）そんなことはないよ
Nothing like that.
（ヤサコ）そう
Is that so?
Sometimes,
時々[ときどき]:sometimes/at times
（ヤサコ）
私 時々 ハラケンが―
I have an anxious feeling, like...
急[きゅう]:urgent|sharp|rapid||, 気がする[きがする]:to have a certain mood or feeling/to have a hunch
急にふっといなくなっちゃうような
そんな気がして…
you might suddenly fade away.
This is our...
私たち[わたしたち, わたくしたち]:we/us, 最後[さいご]:last|no sooner than|one's final moments, 夏休み[なつやすみ]:summer vacation/summer holiday
私たち 最後の夏休みよね？
last summer, isn't it?
Our last?
最後[さいご]:last|no sooner than|one's final moments
（ハラケン）最後の？
ううん:no|er, well, ..., 小学校[しょうがっこう]:primary school/elementary school/grade school, 最後[さいご]:last|no sooner than|one's final moments
（ヤサコ）ああ… ううん
小学校で最後の
I mean, in elementary school.
私たち[わたしたち, わたくしたち]:we/us, もっと:(some) more/even more/longer, 楽しい[たのしい]:enjoyable/fun
（ヤサコ）
私たち もっと楽しいこととか
We should...
do more fun things,
面白い[おもしろい]:interesting|amusing|pleasant
面白いことをやってて
いいんじゃないかなって思うの
or more amusing things. That's what I think.
You're always...
ずっと:continuously in some state (for a long time, distance)/throughout|much (better, etc.)
ハラケンは ずっと…
ずっと:continuously in some state (for a long time, distance)/throughout|much (better, etc.), 気持ち[きもち]:feeling|preparedness|thanks|
この１年 ずっとツラい気持ちで
いたんじゃないかって
You've been
in pain all this year, I'm sure of it.
同じ[おなじ, おんなじ]:same/identical|(usu. part of a 'nara' conditional) anyway
天沢さんと同じで
それを誰にも言わずに１人で…
Just like Amasawa,
you can't tell anyone about it... Alone...
なさる:to do, 変[へん]:strange|unexpected|change||
ご… ごめんなさい
変なこと言ってるわね
S-Sorry...
I'm saying strange things, aren't I?
ただの…
It's just that...
好奇心[こうきしん]:curiosity/inquisitiveness
ただの好奇心なんだ
I was curious...
イリーガル:illegal, 古い[ふるい]:old (not person)/aged/ancient, 空間[くうかん]:space/room/airspace, 空間[あきま]:vacancy/room for rent or lease
イリーガルとか
古い空間とか見てみたくて…
about Illegals.
I just wanted to see how it was...
in obsolete Space.
それだけ
Just that.
なんか:things like .../or something like that ... (often derogatory), なんか:something, 関係[かんけい]:relation|participation|influence||
カンナのことなんか関係ない
This has nothing to do
with Kanna.
とおり:avenue/street|coming and going, とおり:penetration (as of light)
ヤサコの言うとおりだ
It's just like you said.
I think too much.
考える[かんがえる]:to think about|to ponder|to intend||, すぎる:to pass through/to pass by|to pass (i.e. of time)
僕は考えすぎてたんだ
もっと:(some) more/even more/longer, 楽しい[たのしい]:enjoyable/fun
僕たちは もっと楽しいこととか
We... should do more fun things.
面白い[おもしろい]:interesting|amusing|pleasant, 過ごす[すごす]:to pass (time)|to overdo (esp. of one's alcohol consumption)|to take care of||
面白いことをして過ごすべきなんだ
We should spend our time more pleasantly.
ハラケン
Haraken...
なんか:things like .../or something like that ... (often derogatory), なんか:something, 気にする[きにする]:to mind (negative nuance)/to care about/to worry
僕は もう
カンナのことなんか気にしてないよ
I don't care
about Kanna anymore.
心配[しんぱい]:worry/concern|care, ありがとう:Thank you/Thanks
心配してくれてありがとう ヤサコ
Thank you for worrying about me, Yasako.
自由[じゆう]:freedom/liberty/as it pleases you, 研究[けんきゅう]:study/research/investigation, 終わる[おわる]:to finish/to end/to close
だから さっさと自由研究は
終わらせて
So, let's hurry up and finish our independent research,
残り[のこり]:remnant/residue/remaining, 夏休み[なつやすみ]:summer vacation/summer holiday, 楽しい[たのしい]:enjoyable/fun, 過ごす[すごす]:to pass (time)|to overdo (esp. of one's alcohol consumption)|to take care of||
残りの夏休みは楽しく過ごそう
and spend our last summer vacation pleasantly.
プール:(swimming) pool, 遊園地[ゆうえんち]:amusement park
プールに行ったり 遊園地でもいい
Let's go to the pool,
or to the playground.
Let's all play together like crazy.
みたい:-like/sort of/similar to, 騒ぐ[さわぐ]:to make noise|to rustle|to make merry||
みんなでバカみたいに騒ごう
デンパ:electromagnetic wave/radio wave/reception, 呼ぶ[よぶ]:to call out (to)|to summon (a doctor, etc.)|to invite||
ダイチとかデンパも呼んで
Let's invite Daichi,
Denpa and the rest.
ホント:truth/reality/actuality
ホントに？
Really?
Yup.
Haraken...
ハラケン
ハラケン 私…
Haraken, I...
I kinda...
私 ハラケンのこと…
明日[あした, あす]:tomorrow|near future
明日…
Tomorrow...
Let's go to that obsolete Space.
明日[あした, あす]:tomorrow|near future, 古い[ふるい]:old (not person)/aged/ancient, 空間[くうかん]:space/room/airspace, 空間[あきま]:vacancy/room for rent or lease
明日 その古い空間に行ってみよう
見つかる[みつかる]:to be found/to be discovered
それで もし
何も見つからなかったら
If we don't find anything,
the research ends there.
自由[じゆう]:freedom/liberty/as it pleases you, 研究[けんきゅう]:study/research/investigation, おしまい:the end/closing|That's it
自由研究は それでおしまい
Let's get through it quickly and by chance.
適当[てきとう]:suitable/proper|noncommittal, 済む[すむ]:to finish|to merely result in something less severe than expected|to feel at ease|, 終わる[おわる]:to finish/to end/to close
適当に済ませて終わらせちゃおう
楽しい[たのしい]:enjoyable/fun, 場所[ばしょ]:place|room|basho
そのあとは楽しい場所に行こう
After that, let's go someplace nice.
Yup.
It's our...
最後[さいご]:last|no sooner than|one's final moments, 夏休み[なつやすみ]:summer vacation/summer holiday
最後の夏休みだから
last summer vacation, after all.
Yup.
チェッ
Damn!
投げる[なげる]:to throw/to cast away|to face defeat, 段取り[だんどり]:programme/program/plans
おい！
ここは私が投げる段取りだろ
Hey!
We agreed that I would throw it here!
（ナメッチ）
うへ～ す… すんません！
S-Sorry!
役立つ[やくだつ]:to be useful/to be helpful/to serve the purpose, 追いかける[おいかける]:to chase/to run after/to pursue
（イサコ）
役立たずめ！　追いかけるぞ！
You good-for-nothing!
Let's follow it!
いない
It's not here...
てめえ:you (used by young males)|oneself, ずっと:continuously in some state (for a long time, distance)/throughout|much (better, etc.), やがる:verb suffix indicating hatred and contempt, or disdain for another's action
てめえ
ずっとつけてきやがったな！
Damn you! So you were always behind our back!
頼む[たのむ]:to request|to call|to entrust to|
頼む！　イサコに会わせてくれ
Please!
Let me see Isako!
あっ？　何言ってんだ
What are you talking about!
用[よう]:business|use|for the use of ...|
オヤビンになんの用だ？
What do you want from our boss?
言える[いえる]:to be possible to say/to be able to say
君たちには言えない
I can't tell you...
マズい:unappetising|unskillful|ugly|
バカにすんな！
（ナメッチ）マ… マズいよ
Stop fooling me!
H-Hey, it's no good!
こいつをやると
あのオバちゃんが…
If you bully him, his Auntie will...
頼む[たのむ]:to request|to call|to entrust to|, 話をする[はなしをする]:to have a talk/to tell a story
頼む！　話をさせてくれ
Please! Let me speak to her!
What's wrong with this guy?!
（ガチャギリ）なんだ こいつ…
ブロック:to block (e.g. the way), 封鎖[ふうさ]:blockade|freezing (funds)
（オバちゃん）
この３ブロックを ２時間 封鎖しろ
Seal the third block for two hours.
責任[せきにん]:duty/responsibility (incl. supervision of staff)|liability, 取る[とる]:to take|to steal|to eat||
ああ 責任は私が取る
Yeah. I'll take full responsibility.
Isako...
止める[とめる]:to stop|to park|to prevent||, 止める[やめる]:to stop (an activity)/to cease|to cancel, あげる:to raise/to elevate|to do up (one's hair)
イサコ 私が止めてあげる
I'll stop you for your own good.
間違い[まちがい]:mistake|accident|improper conduct (e.g. between man and woman)
あなたのやろうとしていることは
間違いよ
What you're doing is wrong.
クソ！
Crap!
うわ～ 来た！
Oh no!
Don't make any noise!
騒ぐ[さわぐ]:to make noise|to rustle|to make merry||, 暗号[あんごう]:code/password/cipher, 機能[きのう]:function/facility/faculty
騒ぐな！
暗号が機能してるはずだ
The encode is supposed to protect us.
Don't underestimate me.
甘い[あまい]:sweet-tasting|fragrant (smelling)|lightly salted||, 甘い[うまい]:skillful|delicious|fortunate
（オバちゃん）私を甘く見るなよ
とおり:avenue/street|coming and going, とおり:penetration (as of light)
思ったとおりだ
Just like I thought.
暗号[あんごう]:code/password/cipher, ほとんど:mostly/nearly/practically, 解読[かいどく]:deciphering/decoding, 可能[かのう]:potential/possible/practicable
イサコの暗号のほとんどは
解読可能だ
It's possible to decrypt almost all of Isako's encodes.
物理[ぶつり]:physics/law of nature, 結界[けっかい]:(fixing) boundaries for religious practices|prohibition (of items, people, spirits, etc. that would hinder Buddhist practice)|fence between inner and outer sanctums in a temple||, 以外[いがい]:with the exception of/excepting, ほとんど:mostly/nearly/practically, 破れる[われる]:to break|to split|to be divided|, 破れる[やぶれる]:to get torn/to tear|to be broken off (of negotiations, etc.)
物理結界以外なら
ほとんど破れるぞ
At least if they're beyond the physical sphere.
来い ポチ タマ
Come, Pochi, Tama!
今回[こんかい]:now/this time/lately, 容赦[ようしゃ]:pardon/forgiveness|leniency, 総力戦[そうりょくせん]:all-out war/total war
今回は容赦しない
総力戦でいくわよ
This time, I won't tolerate any nonsense.
I'll fight with all my forces.
チビ！
Chibi!
How could I never have imagined that the encode's core is
まさか:by no means/never!|something unexpected, 暗号[あんごう]:code/password/cipher, ルーツ:roots, メタタグ:META tag, 同じ[おなじ, おんなじ]:same/identical|(usu. part of a 'nara' conditional) anyway
まさか暗号のルーツが
メガばあのメタタグと同じとはな
the same as Mega-baa's metatag's?
一体[いったい]:...the heck (e.g. "what the heck?")|one object|one form||, 何者[なにもの]:who/what kind of person
天沢勇子(ゆうこ)
お前は 一体 何者なんだ？
Yuko Amasawa...
Who are you really?
遅い[おそい]:slow|late (e.g. "late at night")|too late|
（ヤサコ）ハラケン遅いな
Haraken is late.
さっき:some time ago/just now, さっき:thirst for blood/bloodlust/determination to kill, ページ:page
（通知音）
（ヤサコ）あっ さっきのページ
The page from before.
新しい[あたらしい]:new/novel/fresh, 質問[しつもん]:question/inquiry/enquiry
新しい質問が入ってる
Oh, there's a new question.
“もし ミチコさんが―”
"If Miss Michiko
願い事[ねがいごと]:wish/dream/prayer, かなえる:to grant (request, wish)/to answer (prayer)|to fulfill (conditions)
“なんでも願い事を
かなえてくれるなら”
can really grant any wish..."
"Maybe she can also heal the pains or injuries of dead people?"
苦しみ[くるしみ]:pain/anguish/distress, 痛み[いたみ]:pain/ache|damage, 癒やす[いやす]:to heal/to cure
“死んだ人の苦しみや痛みも
癒やせますか？”
これって…
This is...
苦しみ[くるしみ]:pain/anguish/distress, 悲しい[かなしい]:sad/sorrowful, 気持ち[きもち]:feeling|preparedness|thanks|
もし 苦しみとか
悲しい気持ちとか
If feelings like pain,
or sadness...
そういうものが…
If these feelings...
原因[げんいん]:cause/origin/source, 作る[つくる]:to make|to prepare (food)|to raise||, 埋め合わせる[うめあわせる]:to make amends/to compensate for/to make up for, 癒やす[いやす]:to heal/to cure, あげる:to raise/to elevate|to do up (one's hair), かぎり:limit/limits|degree
その原因を作った人が埋め合わせて
癒やしてあげないかぎり
If the person at the source of these feelings can't heal them...
ハラケン
Haraken!
ホント:truth/reality/actuality, 捕まえる[つかまえる]:to catch/to arrest/to seize
（ナメッチ）こんなんで
ホントに捕まえられるのかね？
Can we really catch it with this?
多分[たぶん]:perhaps/probably|generous
（ガチャギリ）ああ 多分な
Yeah, maybe.
結界[けっかい]:(fixing) boundaries for religious practices|prohibition (of items, people, spirits, etc. that would hinder Buddhist practice)|fence between inner and outer sanctums in a temple||, 電脳[でんのう]:computer|cyberbrain/digital brain, 物質[ぶっしつ]:material/substance|matter, 遮断[しゃだん]:isolation/cut off/blockade, 同時[どうじ]:simultaneous/concurrent/same time
こいつは結界で
電脳物質を遮断すると同時に
This creates a barrier to intercept the cybersubstance,
レーダー:radar, 代わり[かわり]:substitute|stand-in|compensation||, 代わり[がわり]:substitute for ..., 暗号[あんごう]:code/password/cipher
レーダーの代わりもする暗号だ
and at the same time it's an encoding that works like a radar.
（ナメッチ）
へえー そんなこと分かるの？
Oh, you understand these things?
読む[よむ]:to read|to count|to guess
ああ なんとなく
読めるようになってきたぜ
Yeah,
somehow I've learned to interpret this.
さっき:some time ago/just now, さっき:thirst for blood/bloodlust/determination to kill, イリーガル:illegal, 確実[かくじつ]:certainty/reliability/soundness, キャッチ:catch/catching/obtaining (e.g. information)
これで さっきのイリーガルを
確実にキャッチするつもりだ
We should be able to get that Illegal with 100% certainty.
But even so,
（ナメッチ）それにしても―
目的[もくてき]:purpose/goal/aim, 一体[いったい]:...the heck (e.g. "what the heck?")|one object|one form||
イサコオヤビンの目的って
一体なんなんだろう？
I still wonder what Isako's real motive is.
ちょっと
イヤなウワサを聞いたんだ
I heard a kinda unpleasant rumor...
呼び出す[よびだす]:to summon/to call (e.g. phone)|to invoke (e.g. subroutine)
イサコオヤビンが
あるものを呼び出そうとしてるって
They say that Isako
wants to summon a certain being.
（ガチャギリ）あるもの？
A certain being?
（ナメッチ）ミチコさんを
Miss Michiko.
頭痛[ずつう]:headache
また頭痛だ
Again, the headache...
んっ… 誰？
Who is it?
（ナメッチ）それだけじゃないんだ
Not only that.
呼び出す[よびだす]:to summon/to call (e.g. phone)|to invoke (e.g. subroutine), 生贄[いけにえ]:sacrifice (to the gods)|victim/scapegoat, 欲しい[ほしい]:wanted/wished for|I want (you) to
呼び出されたミチコさんは
生贄(いけにえ)を欲しがるんだって…
I heard that the new-born Michiko
will want a sacrificial victim.
くだる:to descend/to go down|to be handed down (of an order, judgment, etc.), 話[はなし]:talk/speech|discussions, 話[わ]:counter for stories, episodes of TV series, etc.
くだらねえ
そんな話はどうでもいい
That's silly.
I don't care one bit about that story.
暗号[あんごう]:code/password/cipher, 盗む[ぬすむ]:to steal, 恐らく[おそらく]:perhaps/likely/probably, もっと:(some) more/even more/longer, 仕事[しごと]:work/job|work, 使える[つかえる]:to be usable/to be serviceable/to be useful
暗号を盗めば 恐らく
もっとデカい仕事に使える
If we steal the encode,
we might be able to use it in a much bigger job.
狙い[ねらい]:aim
俺の狙いは それだけだ
That's my only objective.
（電子音）
（ナメッチ）あっ 来た
Here it is!
All right!
シフト:shift, 追い込む[おいこむ]:to herd/to corner/to drive
よし シフト２で追い込むぞ！
Corner it with a Shift-Two!
当たる[あたる]:to be hit|to touch|to be equivalent to||
当たった！
（ガチャギリ）よくやった！
Got it!
Well done!
見える[みえる]:to be seen|to look|to come, 見える[まみえる]:to have an audience|to face (an enemy)|to serve (esp. as one's wife)
な… なんで見えてるの？
Wh-Why are we visible?
追う[おう]:to chase|to follow (a set order, a trend, etc.)|to drive out||
追うぞ！
Let's chase it!
（ナメッチ）わあ～！
（２人）ハァ…
（サッチー）ボク サッチー
Me Satchii!
基[もと]:origin|base|cause||, 基[き]:group|(free) radical|counter for installed or mounted objects (e.g. stone lanterns, gravestones, satellites)
（ナメッチ）３…
（ガチャギリ）３基！
Th...
Three?!
（ナメッチ）ひえ～！
（ガチャギリ）ぐわっ…
鉄壁[てっぺき]:iron wall/impregnable fortress
（ガチャギリ）鉄壁だ！
Steel wall!
雑魚[ざこ, じゃこ]:small fish/small fry|person of low social standing
（オバちゃん）
チッ 雑魚はオトリか
The small fishes are decoys.
追う[おう]:to chase|to follow (a set order, a trend, etc.)|to drive out||
イサコだけを追え！
Just follow Isako!
臨界[りんかい]:critical (pressure, temperature, state, point)
これで臨界だ
This is the critical point.
Crap...
（オバちゃん）
クソ！　イサコはどこだ？
Where's Isako?
暗号[あんごう]:code/password/cipher, 構造[こうぞう]:structure/construction/makeup
この暗号の構造は…
The structure of this encode is...
全[ぜん]:all/whole|pan-, 基[もと]:origin|base|cause||, 基[き]:group|(free) radical|counter for installed or mounted objects (e.g. stone lanterns, gravestones, satellites), ポイント:point, 向かう[むかう]:to face|to go towards/to head towards
全基 このポイントに向かえ！
All Satchiis! Go to this point!
Just a little bit more...
あとちょっと…
通路[つうろ]:passage/pathway/roadway, 開く[ひらく]:to open|to bloom|to open (for business, e.g. in the morning)||, 開く[あく]:to open (e.g. doors)|to open (e.g. business, etc.)|to be empty||
あとちょっとで通路が開く！
A little more, and the passage will open!
Now!
今だ！
勝つ[かつ]:to win/to gain victory, 全部[ぜんぶ]:all/entire/whole, 捕まえる[つかまえる]:to catch/to arrest/to seize
（ナメッチ）勝った！
サッチー 全部 捕まえたぞ
We won!
We captured all the Satchiis!
Too bad! And you even sent three of 'em!
基[もと]:origin|base|cause||, 基[き]:group|(free) radical|counter for installed or mounted objects (e.g. stone lanterns, gravestones, satellites), 残念[ざんねん]:deplorable/bad luck/regret
３基も出したのに残念だったな
Crap! A physical barrier!
物理[ぶつり]:physics/law of nature, 結界[けっかい]:(fixing) boundaries for religious practices|prohibition (of items, people, spirits, etc. that would hinder Buddhist practice)|fence between inner and outer sanctums in a temple||
（オバちゃん）
クソ！　物理結界か…
I got them all...
集める[あつめる]:to collect/to assemble/to gather
集めた…
This time...
今度[こんど]:this time|next time|recently
今度こそ
１年前のようなことにはならない
there won't be a repeat of last year!
Me Satchii!
（サッチー）ボク サッチー
ああっ…
（ナメッチ）なんで？
Why?
Enough!
（オバちゃん）ここまでよ
Pochi!
ポチ！　タマ！　チビ！
Tama!
Chibi!
Koro!
コロ！　ミケ！
Mike!
What?!
（２人）何？
基[もと]:origin|base|cause||, 基[き]:group|(free) radical|counter for installed or mounted objects (e.g. stone lanterns, gravestones, satellites)
（ナメッチ）３基…
（ガチャギリ）じゃねえ
They aren't...
Just three!
There are five!
基[もと]:origin|base|cause||, 基[き]:group|(free) radical|counter for installed or mounted objects (e.g. stone lanterns, gravestones, satellites)
（ガチャギリ）５基だ！
Smash the encodes around here!
周囲[しゅうい]:surroundings/environs|circumference, 暗号[あんごう]:code/password/cipher, 潰す[つぶす]:to smash|to shut down|to thwart||
（オバちゃん）周囲の暗号を潰せ！
あっ なんだ？
What's this?
Use all your steel walls!
鉄壁[てっぺき]:iron wall/impregnable fortress, 全て[すべて]:everything/all|entirely
（ガチャギリ）鉄壁 全て使えー！
Smash it!
砕ける[くだける]:to break (into pieces)|to collapse|to become less formal||, 先[さき]:previous|point (e.g. pencil)|head (of a line)||, 先[せん]:former/previous|first move (in go, shogi, etc.)
（オバちゃん）
砕け！　その先にイサコがいる
Isako's just behind that wall!
Be ready the instant it opens!
通路[つうろ]:passage/pathway/roadway, 開く[ひらく]:to open|to bloom|to open (for business, e.g. in the morning)||, 開く[あく]:to open (e.g. doors)|to open (e.g. business, etc.)|to be empty||, 瞬間[しゅんかん]:moment/second/instant, 押さえる[おさえる]:to pin something down|to seize|to gain control of something|
通路を開いた瞬間を押さえる！
This is bad!
マズい:unappetising|unskillful|ugly|
マズい… このままでは―
At this rate,
the control line will break down!
コントロール:control, 系[けい]:system|corollary|system (range of strata that correspond to a particular time period)|, 暗号[あんごう]:code/password/cipher, 破損[はそん]:damage, しまう:to finish/to stop|to close (a business, etc.)
コントロール系の暗号が
破損してしまう
I gotta stop those Satchiis!
止める[とめる]:to stop|to park|to prevent||, 止める[やめる]:to stop (an activity)/to cease|to cancel
あのサッチーを止めなくては―
Otherwise, it will open again at a place I can't control!
コントロール:control, 場所[ばしょ]:place|room|basho, 開く[ひらく]:to open|to bloom|to open (for business, e.g. in the morning)||, 開く[あく]:to open (e.g. doors)|to open (e.g. business, etc.)|to be empty||, しまう:to finish/to stop|to close (a business, etc.)
またコントロールできない場所に
開いてしまう！
Just like...
去年[きょねん, こぞ]:last year
去年の あのときのように…
last year!
You...
お前は…
Why are you here?
なぜ ここに？
Yuko Amasawa.
天沢勇子
I...
君と…
I want to make a trade with you.
取り引き[とりひき]:transactions/dealings/business
君と取り引きしたい
What? A trade?
取り引き[とりひき]:transactions/dealings/business
取り引きだと？
He's not answering...
出ないわ
I don't care
なんか:things like .../or something like that ... (often derogatory), なんか:something, 気にする[きにする]:to mind (negative nuance)/to care about/to worry
僕は もう
カンナのことなんか気にしてないよ
about Kanna anymore.
That space from yesterday...
空間[くうかん]:space/room/airspace, 空間[あきま]:vacancy/room for rent or lease
（ヤサコ）今日の空間…
It's near where Kanna's accident occurred!
事故[じこ, ことゆえ]:accident/incident|circumstances, 近く[ちかく]:near|nearly (e.g. "it took nearly one year")|shortly
カンナちゃんの事故の近くだ
I... can access Satchii's command process.
命令[めいれい]:order/command|(software) instruction, プロセス:process, アクセス:access
（ハラケン）
僕はサッチーの命令プロセスに
アクセスできる
Aunty showed me how.
オバちゃんが
そうしてくれたんだ
The access code...
アクセス:access, コード:code, 教える[おしえる]:to teach|to tell|to preach
そのアクセスコードを君に教える
I'll tell it to you!
What?!
なんだと？
If you use it, I'm sure you can win.
勝つ[かつ]:to win/to gain victory
君なら これを使えば勝てるはずだ
But,
（イサコ）しかし お前がなぜ？
why are you...
What're your...
条件[じょうけん]:condition/conditions/term
お前の… お前の条件はなんだ？
What're your terms?
You...
僕を…
You have to take me to the other side!
あっち:that way (direction distant from both speaker and listener)/over there|that one (something physically distant from both speaker and listener, or something not visible but known by both speaker and listener), 連れる[つれる]:to lead/to take (a person)
僕をあっちに連れて行ってくれ！
Preview
Next time
on Denno Coil:
The door to another world.
The Door to Another World
See you next time!
次回[じかい]:next time (occasion), 電脳[でんのう]:computer|cyberbrain/digital brain, コイル:coil
（ヤサコ）
次回 「電脳コイル」
異界[いかい]:spirit world/underworld/the next world, 扉[とびら]:door/gate|title page
〝異界への扉 〞
楽しみ[たのしみ]:enjoyment/pleasure|anticipation
お楽しみに